Okay, so titles. What
you need to understand
about titles is that
titles are pretty much
just copywriting. And copywriting
is a skill that
impacts your titles, your
thumbnails, your scripts, your
sales pages, your emails.
So what you want
to do is get
very good at it.
So now I'm going
to give you a
little bit of a
lesson on the basics
of copywriting, which we're
then going to bring
into our titles in
particular, as well as
other elements later. So
check out this video,
and then I'll be
back to give you
some title rules.
It's going to impact
your thumbnails, your titles,
your scripts, your sales
page, your emails. It'll
even make everything you
write again, 10 times
more interesting to avatars.
And understanding this now
is going to help
you a ton with
the research task I
give you in the
next video too, because
it's going to enable
you to spot blinding
videos, which is a
good video. And it's
called copywriting. But the
thing that makes this
so powerful is copywriting
isn't about the words
you write. It's about
what the viewer feels
when they read them.
In story, we call
this subtext. The idea
is we write words,
which makes the viewer
feel like they're reading
a book. Viewers connect
the dots so they
can use their brains
to find meaning in
them. When we do
this well, it makes
people really curious to
want to know more.
So they click, they
listen, and they binge.
Now it sounds deep,
right? But I'm going
to give you a
bunch of ways to
really simplify this down
now. The first I
call the Benz system.
This is actually the
brainchild of a copywriting
legend called Carl Milligan.
He called it Nesby.
I just rearranged it
and called it Benz
because I thought it
was easy to remember.
So please pay attention
to this because I'm
going to say Benz
a heck of a
lot in this course
now because it's so
powerful. Each of the
letters in the Benz
system stands for something
which will make your
viewers feel something that
causes some kind of
reaction. Benz basically makes
things more interesting, and
you have to be
interesting to your viewers
as much as possible.
Otherwise, they're going to
watch someone else. So
the first part of
the Benz system is
B. This stands for
big. So no matter
if you're coming up
with a title or
a hook or an
intro, you really want
your viewers to feel
like they're going to
get a big result
from whatever it is
you're saying. I mean,
think about it. Why
would someone waste time
on something that didn't
feel like it was
going to have a
meaningful impact on their
life? Now, this means
you're going to have
to get used to
big drama and making
big claims and your
thumbnails and your titles
and your scripts, which
makes a lot of
people feel uncomfortable, but
it's a critical part
of the game everyone
plays. So don't let
your competition get the
upper hand whilst you
sit by ignoring it,
going, oh, I'm not
going to do it
that way. Trust me,
I was that guy
for years. It didn't
work. Next, we have
E, which stands for
Ed. No, I'm joking.
Next, we have E
that stands for easy.
So if I told
you that in order
to grow a YouTube
channel, all you need
to do is one
thousand different things over
the next seven years,
would you do it?
No, you wouldn't. And
that's why we need
to make it feel
like what we're going
to teach people to
get that big result
is going to be
easy too. This is
a power play because
if you make it
sound easy in your
thumbnail and title, you're
going to be forced
to write a script
that makes it easy
for the viewers to
understand and get a
result from too. So
everyone wins. Next, we
have the N, which
means new. This is
the most powerful of
the bunch. Why? Well,
because most of your
viewers will be frustrated
and they'll have tried
to solve their problem.
Doing other things people
have told and they'll
be blaming everyone apart
from themselves. So if
we can make it
sound like our information
is new, it's a
game changer because they'll
be more inclined to
click and keep listing
in search of that
new game changing piece
of advice that will
change their life that
makes them feel like
all their mistakes wasn't
really their fault in
the end and they
can blame everyone else
online. The thing is,
what if your info
isn't new? Well, don't
panic. It probably won't
be. Read Horne Mosey's
book, 100 Million Dollar
Lease. It's pretty much
just Russell Bronson's book
and a load of
old school business advice
that's been around for
years. Just repackaged in
a way that feels
new because he uses
his own unique stories
to make his point.
So just keep in
mind new is exciting
and hooks people, but
the info just needs
to feel new to
the viewers and the
way you tell stories
and use metaphors, I'll
teach you to do
another time is going
to do this. And
then we have S,
which stands for safe.
Now there's so much
crap online, viewers, cold
in particular, just do
not trust creators. It's
why they won't click
on people they've not
seen before in the
same way they will
on a creator they've
been watching for years.
So we need to
find ways to make
our videos feel new.
So if you're a
fan of social media,
you might want to
make sure you're not
making videos that are
just about making people
feel safe to them.
This is why social
hacking works really well.
So making videos about
Mr. Beast and Elon
Musk, these explode because
they have a trusted
face on. Your face
probably has no meaning.
No offense. So it
might not make people
feel safe. So now
we know the basics
to copywriting, which we're
going to use in
thumbnails, titles, intros, and
our scripts and our
sales pages and our
emails and our social
media. Anything else? I
think. Let's break down
some amazing videos that
use Benz to get
big views. Understanding this
is really going to
help you with the
next video when we
start to research and
pull apart channels to
learn how to get
more views. Starting with
this video, which is
an amazing example of
big in action. In
fact, I go so
far to say this
is one of the
best YouTube titles of
all time in this
niche. It really just
stops you in your
track. How to get
so rich you question
the meaning of making
money. I mean, I
mean, firstly, so rich
is a big claim,
but question the meaning
of making money. That's
the biggest claim ever.
Big in this case
is almost so big.
It's almost all you
need. Then we have
easy. Well, to me,
this isn't as strong
in the title. Doesn't
sound easy. The same
time it doesn't sound
hard. So I'm not
put off. Oh, and
by the way, there's
subjective opinions here. You
might feel very differently
about this, but you
have to remember YouTube
is about appealing to
your target viewers, not
everyone. So you could
read between the lines
in a different way.
New. Now this sounds
new to me because
I've never actually heard
anyone say this before.
Like it's usually how
to make a hundred
K, but this is
the biggest thing I've
ever heard. So the
info feels like it's
maybe going to be
new to me. But
also he's not really
given away too much
about what the video
is about. So I'm
kind of intrigued and
then safe because it's
for Mosey, you know,
this guy's got credibility
coming out of his
ears. He should probably
go and see a
doctor about that. But
if he was a
nobody, what might make
you feel safe? Well,
the claims actually so
big. I personally feel
like only someone who
knows what they're talking
about would write such
like this. So I
feel a bit safer,
but again, to me,
big and new are
the main drivers of
this one. What's important
to remember here is
it's not a case
of getting bends into
all of them, a
B or an E
or an N or
an S. Well, it's
a lot of value
in this video. So
let's read between the
lines because that's what
great copy does. The
subtext here, as in
the words that are
not on the screen,
the viewers then fill
in the gaps with
their own mind is,
I want that kind
of money. This sounds
like life changing information
I can trust. What
do I need to
do and get that?
Okay. Next we have
a video that has
blown up on multiple
channels in all kinds
of niches. All of
them straight away lead
with big. So a
hundred books is a
lot of content to
consume and change my
life. Well, that's a
big claim. What's the
view of thinking? Well,
sounds like there's a
lot of value in
this video. I'm not
sure if I'm right
or not. Then easy.
Well, the thing that
makes this feel easy
to me is, well,
they've done all the
hard work for me.
Clark's video in particular,
I think is strong
because he says there's
three lessons from 100
books, three lessons. It
just sounds really easy
to digest, right? If
he'd said 350 lessons,
I might've been more
put off. Then there's
new. To me, I've
not read 100 books,
probably ever. So I
feel like there's going
to be a lot
in there that I
don't know. And that
makes the promise of
this video feel safe.
And this is one
of the powerful things
about videos that are
packaged up like a
challenge that if you
really want to leave
a mark on your
niche, I'd recommend you
do because they said
you did the thing.
It's not I tried
to it's I did.
And that makes me
feel safe. There's going
to be value in
this and it won't
waste my time. And
then all of these
things combined make the
title and packaging very
intriguing. So it gets
a click. Okay. Let's
look at one more.
Oh, it's one of
mine. How embarrassing, but
it's a good one
because firstly big, well,
I made it sound
like there's a sneaky
thing. YouTubers are doing
to hook you something
you can't hear, which
kind of makes it
sound like a big
claim that the viewers
are going to want
to know what the
hell is that thing
easy. Well, I think
it's a hack is
supposed to make it
sound easy. That's why
hack videos are popular
safe. I've not said
I do this. I've
said the two massive
YouTube is my audience
respect do. So I've
harnessed their credibility to
get a click and
new. I didn't name
the hack, which makes
it more mysterious. If
I called it how
YouTubers use body language.
Yeah, that's that video
would have been dead.
So the subtext here
is the viewers feel
like they are being
let in on a
secret. Something is easy
and there's credibility and
there's a novel strategy
that could give them
an edge. Playing on
their own. I'm not
going to lie. I'm
not going to lie.
I'm not going to
lie. I'm not going
to lie. I'm not
going to lie. I'm
not going to lie.
I'm not going to
lie. I love the
novelty. It's pretty proud
of that one.
I guess as I
mentioned, you don't have
to get all four
in. Don't sit there
thinking this is the
ultimate goal. But for
your packaging and interest
in particular, you need
to create intrigue and
using the band system
will enable you to
do this. But it's
really important to use
copywriting in the tile
and thumbnail. We're going
to be looking a
lot more at thumbnails
in coming modules, but
a channel that's really
good at this is
charisma on command. They
use words like tricks
in their thumbnails to
make it sound easy
and new and they
put big claims in
their titles too. Just
look at the words
they use. There is
nothing lukewarm about this.
The words are powerful.
Other creators do this
in a way where
they name their systems
or rules to make
it sound like they
have a new process
you can use to
get a result, which
makes it sound easy.
A channel I was
working on that follows
the exact thumbnail and
title system I'm going
to teach you exploded
when they switched a
video thumbnail to this.
Why? Well, you feel
safe with this graph,
right? It's like they
have it all planned
out and then 15
seconds, well, that's easy
to do and the
results they claim is
also massive. So it's
big. So your thumbnail
and title have to
work together as a
team to follow the
system, which is designed
to make everything you
do more intriguing, more
exciting and more effective.
And you have to
inject this into your
thumbnails and titles and
your chosen writing. After
Benz, there's a couple
more tools to play
with too. So the
next is all about
building more trust with
your viewers, which in
turn will make them
feel safer. And you
do that by being
specific, which gets confusing
because I'm going to
tell you to be
less specific with your
packaging so that you
can get more clicks,
but I'm also going
to tell you to
be more specific with
your packaging so you
can get more clicks.
So let me explain.
What I mean by
specific in the good
sense, to get more
views and hold attention
longer is this. What
we want to do
is pitch a specific
result in our thumbnails
and titles. In its
simplest form saying make
$14 ,322 is specific
versus make money, which
is not. Specific attributes
in your copy are
more believable. They sound
safer because it feels
like you've put in
the work to actually
figure something out. So
we want to be
specific about things like
results and that often
comes in the form
of time, money, speed,
distance, age. There's a
lot of different ways
which you're going to
see in a minute.
The next tool is
very powerful because it
will get you more
clicks or cause viewers
to take action on
what you've taught them
to get the result
they want, which means
you'll build more fans
and they'll understand why
they need to keep
listening to you. It's
called urgency. Urgency creates
stakes and you'll be
learning a lot more
about stakes and their
power soon, but put
it this way, they
are critical for retention
and clicks. So let
me give you some
examples of these in
action. Here's Shelby Church
using specific to make
a title and thumbnail
more unique. If she'll
be able to do
that, she'll be removing
400 square foot. It
kinda wrecks it, right?
Then this from James
Dunn. He used the
thumbnail to make the
result specific with the
time saving. It's a
big claim. Sounds easy,
because you're not going
to get tired. It
sounds unique and new
with not what you
think in the title.
It's kind of ticking
every box, but maybe
urgent. Again, please don't
worry about getting 100
% of the things
I show you into
a thumbnail and title.
We'll use the intro
and the content to
harness them a lot
too. You just need
to make sure they
include some of them.
And then here's an
example of a copy
that goes to town
on a lot of
these things. Firstly, big.
I mean, the entire
economy about to collapse
is not a small
claim. It's new info
because it's new. It's
specific because it's saying
it's got 29 days
to go. And man,
is it urgent. I
mean, the stakes are
very high for us
if this happens, which
is why he got
1 .8 million views.
This is one of
the things that makes
news -based content so
powerful, but it does
have some drawbacks too,
because it's not ever
green. So I wouldn't
recommend building a channel
solely off news for
that reason. Anyway, that's
a story for another
day. Which brings us
on to some of
the things that are
going to happen in
the future. So let's
get into some title
writing basics and putting
it simply, use bends
and try not to
write titles about 50
characters long. For two
reasons. Firstly, the less
words to read, the
easier it is for
the information to sink
into the viewer's head.
So it really is
key to keep them
short. And secondly, because
after 50 characters, YouTube
cuts off the words
anyway, so nobody sees
them. We don't need
to keyword stuff anymore.
YouTube listens to your
video transcript. It looks
at every frame of
footage to work out
what it's about. So
don't fall into the
trap of just jamming
in extra words because
you think it helps.
If it puts off
humans, it puts off
YouTube. Okay, so a
quick summary. Copywriting is
a power skill that
will get you more
clicks, longer watch time,
more sales, and it's
all about hooking viewers
to pay attention and
stay interested using words
that make big claims,
making things sound new,
safe and easy. You
can also use specific
numbers and amounts to
sound more believable and
create urgency. Okay, so
now you understand bends,
which is a word
you're probably going to
hear us say a
lot. Let's look at
a few little title
rules. So the first
things first is we
always want to try
and keep our titles
under 50 characters. If
it goes over 50,
what happens is, in
certain places on YouTube
where it is displayed,
it won't show over
50 characters, so we
could have important words
cut off. But also,
shorter titles are fastest
to read, and that
is a good thing.
We want speed because
if we can get
a lot of information
into a viewer's brain
fast, they're more likely
to click. We then
want to make sure
that they're clear, they're
not like really vague
or confusing. And what
you tend to find
is titles that set
up a specific benefit
or problem tend to
do better. We also
want to make them
build curiosity and intrigue.
And then this is
something not enough people
talk about, but I
want you to keep
in mind. We want
to make sure they're
a match for our
credibility. So if you
went and made this
video, you took this
title, 13 years of
no BS business advice
in 79 minutes, would
someone who's never heard
of you watch that?
I mean, would you
listen to a random
person talk for 79
minutes? No, this works
for Alex Hormozy because
Alex Hormozy is famous.
So he has a
huge fan base and
return audience base. They
probably saw that and
thought, I'll give that
a shot. It probably
gave it tons of
satisfaction, so YouTube just
pushed it out to
more people, and that's
why it got millions
of views. But what
you tend to find
is if you don't
have that pre -existing
credibility that everyone has,
you're going to have
a lot of people
who are knows about,
it can be harder
to get a click.
So try to avoid
things like my morning
routine and 79 minutes
of advice and how
I comb my hair,
because the eye, when
you are not that
well known, can often
hold you back. Okay,
so some mistakes you
need to avoid is
copying titles from large
creators without the credibility,
assuming familiarity, which I've
just mentioned, relying on
AI. So although we're
going to use AI
to write titles, we
don't say, give me
a title and just
use whatever crap it
spits out, because it's
actually very bad at
titles unless you're using
the tools I give
you. We also want
to avoid using colons
in titles that split
them up. They make
the title look crap,
harder to read, but
they're also very AI
and people don't like
that. We don't stuff
keywords and make our
titles super long, hoping
they'll rank in search,
because search doesn't even
work like that anymore.
YouTube will work out
what your video is
about based on the
transcript and every second
of footage it has,
it analyzes. So it
doesn't need keywords. And
then using this weird
line in a title
to break it up.
We just want a
very simple title that's
easy to read without
loads of clutter. But
Ed, this doesn't make
sense, does it? Because,
well, you've probably seen
all of these rules
that I'm telling you,
you need to follow
broken a thousand times
on YouTube. And that
is the thing that
these rules are guides.
They're benchmarks we should
all start from. But
if through your testing
and measuring, you find
out, oh, I can
make a video called
how I comb my
hair and everyone clicks
on it. We do
more of it, right?
So we start with
these rules, but sometimes
your viewers might like
them to be broken.
The other thing I
just want to point
out is I have
made a title bank
for you. You are
going to do a
video called how I
comb my hair and
everyone clicks on it.
So you can see
what titles to make
that appeal to your
viewers. But this is
also there to give
you a little helping
hand. These are titles
that were performed on
other channels that you
could maybe go to
for inspiration if you're
running out of ideas
and go, can I
change this word so
it applies to my
niche? We're going to
learn more about titles
when we start doing
research. But those are
the basic rules for
now. Next, let's get
on to thumbnails.